[orchestral fanfare]
[Star Wars theme]
♪ ♪
(male announcer)
Darkness on Dagobah!
All attention
is focused on Yoda,
who claims to hear the voice
of a long-dead Jedi.
Convinced that he is guided
by Qui-Gon Jinn,
he finds five priestesses
who will teach him
how to manifest consciousness
after death.
After many trials,
Yoda travels to Moraband,
ancient home planet
of the Sith,
for now he must face
the true evil
that may be his undoing
and one that seeks
to control the galaxy.
[R2-D2 hums]
Careful we must be.
Deserted this planet was,
long ago after many wars.
[engine whirring]
[R2-D2 beeping]
Again, leave you I must,
my friend.
Guard the ship you will.
If return I do not
by three nightfalls,
take the ship to Coruscant
you shall.
Tell them of where I went.
[R2-D2 beeping rapidly]
[antenna warbling]
[wind whistling]
[indistinct operatic singing]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[faint hissing and growling]
We are the Sith.
Afraid of you I am not.
We shall see.
[faint hissing and growling]
There is no life after death.
Only nothingness awaits you,
Jedi.
Your fear feeds
our hunger for power.
They will know you are here.
We will tell them.
You will die
and be nothing.
Sir, you have been ordered
to go to Coruscant immediately.
Tell Lord Sidious
I am on my way.
♪ ♪
[flames crackling]
Why do you come to my tomb,
Jedi?
To learn.
Do you know who I am?
Yes.
Darth Bane.
The ancient Sith Lord,
you are.
And know why
I am not forgotten?
Created the Rule of Two
you did.
The Sith killed each other...
Victims of their own greed.
But from the ashes
of destruction,
I was the last survivor.
I chose to pass my knowledge
on to only one.
I created a legacy
so resilient
that now you come before me.
[laughs]
Have you come
to be my apprentice?
You must kill me
to gain my place.
Dead you are already.
[laughing]
Then what stands before you?
An illusion.
Real you are not.
You do not fear me?
No.
Exist you do not anymore.
[wind whistling]
No!
(female voice)
Yoda...
I sense we have
a great opportunity
to strike a deadly blow
to the Jedi Order.
But we must act swiftly.
[whooshing]
A warning I must give you.
Yes.
All your trials
you have faced
have been our doing.
And you have passed them well.
But inside, there is a place
where we have no control,
for it is a place
of absolute darkness.
What happened here?
It is the chamber
where the Sith
would sacrifice Jedi.
The Sith of your time
will find you there,
and you will find them.
Be careful,
for what they may offer
will certainly
feel like an answer.
Only the presence
of someone significant to you
would allow you
to sense this ripple
through time and space.
My old master...
Yoda.
Yes.
Master Yoda
has come to Moraband,
although why,
I do not know.
We shall, however,
use the strong bond
that once existed
between you and your master
to allow us to see things
that we otherwise could not.
How can this be done,
Master?
It is an old art
of the dark side.
Now, hold out your hand,
Apprentice.
I need but a drop
for the ritual to begin.
Kintik hadzuska sutta
chwituskak!
Kintik hadzuska
sutta chwituskak!
Jiaasjen Jidai,
jiassjen Jidai!
Now, concentrate
on Master Yoda.
Bring all your focus to him.
But will he not sense
our presence?
[laughing]
We shall come to him
with a familiar face,
a long-lost face,
one he would be eager
to see again,
one whom he would ask
and want answered
all the questions he seeks.
Help me.
Please, please free me.
Sifo-Dyas?
Alive you are!
Help me, please, Yoda.
I have been imprisoned
for so long.
Know who did this to you?
[chuckles]
What if I could tell you
who the Sith Lord is?
Free me,
and I will reveal it.
No!
[sighs]
He knows how to achieve
what you seek.
Captivated by
the physical realm the Sith are.
What else is there?
Free me,
and together we can know
who the Sith Lord is,
gain the power
you deserve,
and save the future.
No.
You must free me!
Nothing to show me
the Sith have.
We shall see.
[laughing]
Sidious...
There is no question.
The ship was carrying
Count Dooku.
We've scanned the area,
and he is meeting with someone
inside the building.
(Anakin)
Thanks, Rex.
Master Yoda,
what are your orders?
Orders?
Are you all right, Master?
Where am I?
I don't understand.
Tell me you must!
The industrial sector
on Coruscant.
What is happening here?
A rogue shuttle slipped
through the security grid.
We suspect Dooku
was on board.
And?
Master,
this is your mission.
Are you sure
you're all right?
Clouded, the dark side
has made me.
Tell me, who is inside?
We intercepted a transmission
calling Dooku to Coruscant.
We believe he is meeting
with his master,
the Sith Lord.
Feel it I do.
Feel their power.
Your orders, Master?
Capture them we will.
The time has come
to discover the identity
of this Sith Master.
And if they escape?
Escape, not.
If it comes to it...
Execute them we must.
End it now we will.
Move in.
I've got two
confirmed targets.
Be ready for additional
unfriendlies.
It appears we have...
company.
Take 'em!
[blasters firing]
[shouting]
We meet at last,
Darth Sidious.
You cannot stop
what is to come.
[yells]
Skywalker, no!
[lightsabers clashing]
No!
[strangled groaning]
[electricity zapping]
[yelling]
[laughing]
[metal creaking]
Save him, Jedi?
Can you save him?
[electricity zapping]
Why not let him go?
Let him die,
and you can stop
all that I will do.
[electricity zapping]
No!
The future is not yours yet.
Tempted I will not be.
Sacrifice all
I am ready to do.
[Darth Sidius laughing]
[metal crunching]
[growls]
[laughing]
We have failed to break
Master Yoda.
He is strong.
We will need more time
if we are to defeat him
and the Jedi.
Yoda...
Come back to us, Yoda.
Died have I?
In a way.
Now does my training begin?
The one you know
as Qui-Gon Jinn
will commune with you
and guide your training.
Like us, you shall learn
to maintain your consciousness
after death.
Enlightenment,
spirit,
balance...
There is another
Skywalker...
(Yoda)
There is another...
[baby crying]
Skywalker?
[crying fades]
[R2-D2 beeping]
Yes, time to go home
it is.
The Council has assembled.
They are eager
to hear your report.
Afraid not much there is
to say of my journey.
So nothing significant
happened to you out there?
Yes...
And no.
To the end
we are coming now.
Did your journey
give you insight
on how to win the war?
No longer certain
that one ever does win a war
I am.
For in fighting the battles,
the bloodshed already lost
we have.
Yet, open to us,
a path remains
that unknown to the Sith is.
Through this path,
victory we may yet find.
Not victory
in the Clone Wars
but victory for all time.
[R2-D2 beeping]
www.tvsubtitles.net